Welcome back to today's another new tutorial topic, so to this topic for now creating the MongoDB file queries using the table information for the MongoDB shell, okay?
So here I can perfectly explore for the, how to query for the MongoDB collection effectively using the various right array as savings, okay? So now just let's get started, so first of all here I can just go straight for here the MongoDB shell and now next step, so here this is the MongoDB campus and now here I can create for this is
all most students are already now here I create the shell, so now here I can choose for the student database and in this insight for the collection and just using the students collection, okay?
So now just working for the MongoDB shell inside, okay? So now let's get started. So first of all here just to ensure here is perfectly disconnected this MongoDB instantly appropriate this database so perfectly working, so now go for here the sharing side and now first of all here I can just say for here this students inside and now you can here I can choose for
perfectly choose the students database, okay? So now I can start for first of all here I can just use for the first example just finding all the documents in the collections, okay?
So first of all here I can use the service like the DB dot here I can choose the students, okay? So the stu dnts students dot here I can use this is the find perfect type this is the find function, okay?
So first I'll create the double parenthesis and also here I can create the double parenthesis, okay? So you can see here perfectly defined and now just here I can create and you can see here perfectly see all the table information so now perfectly working and this is the find function, okay?
As you can see here this is perfectly executing this query written for all the documents in the students collection, okay? So I hope you understand it so now we are going for another example so here we can just find the documents based on the space pick conditions, okay?
So here the same process follows so first I can type for the given and then can be again used for the collections name suppose the students perfectly type so the stu dnts students you can see here the students here I can type this the find function, okay?
In this inside now first of all I can type for the double here the quotation starting and closing now here type for the curly brackets, okay?
Now here we can type for each these lower and now again just type for the quotation and now I can just define for first of all here must be used for the daughter side and just type with the gt
and now here this the inside is the third, okay? So now here this is perfectly just created and this format returns for the document for the each field is greater than or equal to third, okay?
So now here this is complete and right here this the enter button and you can see here this is the result perfectly show the age is name of the Johan the name is Bob and the Sarah and Bob ages 30 35 40 and 35, okay?
So I hope you perfectly understand the and executing this query or the age field is greater than or equal to 30, okay? We can choose here and use for another example so now here you can find for this document with the nested fields, okay?
So here I can just again use for the dv so now just notice the dv so the daughter I can just type back in the collections name suppose students dot use for again the fine function, okay?
Now here I can choose for that dress column, okay?
So first of all I can create the parentheses and also create the curly brackets, okay? So now in this inside first of all I can create for the double quotation inside define for the address column plot for the city, okay?
And now here I can create the plot and now define for the city name suppose like the new year so this one is perfectly created the new year, okay? So now here the command is completely created and here this comment is we tried document for the city field within the address sub documents in the newer, okay?
So now just create center and you can see in this state fence for here it is created for this so now just just again so here I can just copy, okay?
Again just here defined for the gv so and this code this and now just I can press for the enter and you can see here find this working so now it is not defined so now here I can create for that dress so here I can only use for the city so now here I can just change for this so find
for here I can just simply use for the city and now change for the city is change for here I can just use for the city name is Chicago, okay?
So now it is perfectly defined for the Chicago and now just here I can place for here just last and then press enter and this requirement is not defined, okay? So first statement perfectly working and this statement is correct, okay?
So here I can just go for this and now you can see here I can just go for this and here I can search for the first column for the city we can perfectly use the data, okay?
So I hope people can understand this topic so thank you for watching and happy coding, okay?